[{"question": "OSI - Open Systems Interconnection is bulid on ___ layers.", "answer": "7", "answers": ["4", "2", "8", "7"]}, {"question": "Network access layer in TCP/IP model is responsible for...", "answer": "defining access methods to physical network links.", "answers": ["displaying request status.", "nothing.", "defining access methods to physical network links.", "routing."]}, {"question": "Application layer protocols are:", "answer": "SMTP, FTP, HTTP, SSH", "answers": ["IPv4, IPv6", "SMTP, FTP, HTTP, SSH", "TCP, UDP", "DHCP, DNS"]}, {"question": "TCP protocol is ...", "answer": "all of the above.", "answers": ["used in transportation layer.", "does't allow loss of packets.", "uses 3-way handshake process.", "all of the above."]}, {"question": "Routing details are assigned to packets in...", "answer": "internet layer.", "answers": ["network access layer.", "internet layer.", "transportation layer.", "application layer."]}, {"question": "IP's (Internet Protocol) main job is to...", "answer": "deliver data to target host only by using IP address.", "answers": ["deliver data to target host only by using IP address.", "set up HTTP.", "map IP address and domain name.", "ensure that  there is no packet loss during communication."]}, {"question": "Mapping IP and MAC addresses is a job of...", "answer": "ARP", "answers": ["SSH", "IP", "ARP", "ISP"]}, {"question": "ICMP protocol is used by ___ tool.", "answer": "ARP", "answers": ["grep", "chmod", "ls", "ping"]}, {"question": "___ is a protocol used in time sensetive communication.", "answer": "UDP", "answers": ["UDP", "TCP", "SFTP", "TCP"]}, {"question": "DNS (dns resolver) is...", "answer": "providing mapping for IP addresses and domain names.", "answers": ["Dynamic Network System", "providing mapping for IP addresses and domain names.", "mail-transfer protocol.", "None of the above."]}, {"question": "'HTTP 403'...", "answer": "indicates that the server understands the request but refuses to authorize it.", "answers": ["indicates that resource doesn't exist", "indicates internal server error.", "indicates that the server doesn't understands the request.", "indicates that the server understands the request but refuses to authorize it."]}, {"question": "What is the difference between HTTP and HTTPS?", "answer": "HTTPS uses TLS protocol to encode data sent between client and server.", "answers": ["The is no difference.", "HTTP is safer.", "HTTPS uses TLS protocol to encode data sent between client and server.", "HTTPS uses TLS to ensure 3-hand shake communication."]}, {"question": "Which protocols can be used to ensure additional security layer for FTP protocol?", "answer": "All of the below.", "answers": ["All of the below.", "SSH", "TLS", "SSL"]}, {"question": "Which service must be running on the router for the router to change source and destination IP addresses when forwarding packets between networks?", "answer": "NAT", "answers": ["RIP", "LDAP", "DNS", "NAT"]}, {"question": "What is SSH protocol used for?", "answer": "Safe access to remote machines.", "answers": ["Safe access to remote machines.", "Send emails.", "Private Chat", "All of the above."]}, {"question": "Choose protocol used by email servers.", "answer": "SMTP", "answers": ["RIP", "LDAP", "SMTP", "NAT"]}, {"question": "Which of the following addresses is in the same subnet as the address 10.72.127.15/11 ?", "answer": "10.52.127.15/11", "answers": ["10.52.127.15/11", "10.42.127.15/11", "10.92.127.15/11", "None of the above."]}, {"question": "Which of the following is a valid IPv6 address?", "answer": "2001:DB8::BAF:FE94", "answers": ["2001.DB8.BAF.FE94", "2001:DB8::BAF:FE94", "2001:DB8::BAF::FE94", "2001-DB8-BAF-FE94"]}, {"question": "Which of the following hsa to be configured on server to make it serve content to clients?", "answer": "IP", "answers": ["backup", "IP", "DHCP", "RDS"]}, {"question": "The administrator that gives private addresses in class C with 24 bit mask for computers in the local network will select the range:", "answer": "192.168.0.1 - 192.168.10.254", "answers": ["192.168.0.1 - 192.168.0.254", "192.168.0.1 - 192.168.10.254", "172.16.0.1 - 172.16.255.254", "172.168.0.1 - 172.168.255.254"]}, {"question": "If total number of hosts in a subnet is 16, total number of usable hosts will equal ...", "answer": "14", "answers": ["20", "18", "16", "14"]}, {"question": "TCP/IP is bulid on ___ layers.", "answer": "4", "answers": ["7", "4", "2", "5"]}]